-Now, who shall we choose?
-How exciting.
At that moment, my brain couldn't comprehend what had happened.
I think we should choose him.
What a coincidence, I want him too.
I couldn't comprehend the meaning of losing here.
Come.
Bachira Meguru.
Hurry up so we can advance.
Don't zone out, bowl cut.
Until the very end, I wanted to be with Isagi.
I have to go, it's the rule.
But I won't wait for you, Isagi.
If you want me, come and get me.
From now on,
I'll chase after.
To get back the precious thing I lost.
2ND STAGE 2-ON-2 RIVALRY BATTLE
MATCHING ROOM
So when you lose at 3-on-3, you end up here.
Seems like we're the first ones here.
Yeah.
What should we do?
Looks like there's a place to rest.
Should we go check it out?
Is this really the time to rest?
If we lose again, we're done.
We'll win next time. Our opponents were just too strong this time.
That's not the point.
I'm different from you.
I,
I couldn't do anything against them.
What are you talking about? You scored a goal too.
That was the result of our three-man team play.
Isn't that what soccer is all about?
No!
I'm talking about how I couldn't fight
when our team play was shut down!
I couldn't create a chemical reaction like you and Bachira did.
That's all there is to it.
If we lose again, the one who'll be chosen is you, Nagi.
I won't be chosen.
If I were them, I wouldn't choose myself either.
Are you kidding me, Isagi?
If you're in this state, what about me?
I joined you thinking I'd become stronger if I played with you.
But you being this weak just gets in my way.
Get a hold of yourself, you leech.
What, so you're blaming me?
Put in more effort.
Reo wouldn't have been this weak.
What's that supposed to mean? Go team up with Reo then!
Don't just compare us on a whim and force your ideals on me!
What else can I do? I've never played soccer with anyone else before him.
So you're useless without Reo?
You're saying that, even though you're useless without Bachira?
Stop.
You're right.
That's what's pissing me off.
Damn it!
If you want me, come and get me.
I'll follow the monster inside me.
What's wrong with him?
I'll show that I can fight even without Bachira.
Is that what this selection is about?
What?
I still don't understand soccer very well, but
until now, as long as there was someone who made one from zero,
it was enough for the others to play in a way that elevated that one to a hundred.
But in the second selection, there are fewer players and the field is smaller.
Individual play
has a much greater impact.
What's being tested is our individual skills.
I see.
What we were trying to do,
we couldn't get anywhere with assists or set plays.
Yeah.
It might work against weaker opponents, but
from now on, individual battles will be at the forefront.
no matter who your teammates or opponents are,
you have to win your one-on-ones.
That's the key to surviving the second selection.
There's one more thing, Isagi.
How do I get rid of this feeling of anger?
I'm sorry, but Nagi,
by winning.
Otherwise, this pain won't go away.
Barou.
What do you know.
So if your team sucks, you get thrown into a place like this.
Isn't there anyone strong here?
The key to passing the second selection
is individual strength.
If I can't become strong enough to beat this guy
-I can't survive.
-Get out of my way.
But how can I win against Barou?
It's pretty surprising you're here. Weren't you the strongest?
Want to play with us?
I think I can beat you right now.
Who's beating who?
Me and Isagi, you.
You, who's nothing more than ball control,
shall I personally crush you as the king?
You still call yourself a king even after losing.
I'll defeat you and make you my servant.
Wait, Nagi. Don't provoke him.
I still don't believe I can beat Barou.
'Before the next match,
you must wait 24 hours.' It says.
I'm talking to both of you.
Naruhaya!
Who was that?
My former teammate.
More importantly, you teamed up with Barou?
The other guy was Nishioka, the Messi of Aomori,
but as soon as the match started, Barou scored 4 goals straight away.
But the other team scored 5, so we lost.
Since Barou played too selfishly,
they didn't choose him thinking he'd disrupt the balance.
So the two of us were left.
We lost because you're talentless.
Stop making stupid moves.
Come on, let's just calm down for now.
There's no need to rush and clash with them.
After all, it's over if we lose again.
Right, Isagi?
What? Yeah.
I'm not running or hiding.
If you want to get crushed, come at me anytime.
Losers.
See you later, Isagi!
Okay.
Look, Isagi.
A prison, sideways.
After all, this place is a 'Blue Prison'.
There's a regular bath and cafeteria, but
compared to before, the quality seems to have dropped.
The biggest difference is
that we can use the Blue Lock Men in the training room.
Hey, Isagi.
Why didn't you say let's clash with Barou?
I thought it would be good to add him to our team.
That's true, but in our current state...
What exactly are we lacking?
What I realized in our match against Rin's team,
our weapons can only be utilized as long as we receive passes.
Now I understand.
Mine is ball control and yours is the direct shot.
Yes.
Unless there is someone who understands our weapons like Bachira and Reo,
meaning someone with great passes, we can't stand out.
So how do we use our weapons without passes?
Dribbling, agility,
long limbs, monstrous strength...
We have no chance of winning against those in a one-on-one.
That's precisely what we're lacking.
How do we win one-on-ones without passes?
That's so much harder.
Sorry, it seemed like too much of a hassle.
We'll think about it tomorrow.
Yeah, you're right.
He looks like a mummy.
How can we win?
What does one-on-one strength even mean?
2ND STAGE
CAFETERIA
Those who lost and dropped stages are packed in here.
But more importantly, Isagi, this is a disaster. This cafeteria,
they only serve natto and pickled radish.
Fool, I got used to it a long time ago.
So what are we going to do, Isagi?
Which team will we clash with?
Well,
if we choose a team weaker than us, it'd be easy, but
adding such a person to our team won't be useful later on
and we'll end up back at this point.
Also, at that moment, I'd probably lose Nagi.
It's better to beat the strong ones
and add them to our team, but
since our chances of losing increase, we can't just pair with anyone randomly.
Seems like everyone is thinking the same thing and assessing the situation.
Yeah.
This is the essence of the rivalry battle. Rather than just winning,
we can't move forward without considering how useful the person we team up with will be.
My direct shots are improving.
But I couldn't do anything in a real match.
They have the talent to dominate one-on-ones and create chances.
The ones I have to surpass are these monsters.
The power to dominate in one-on-ones and create chances.
To find the clue to do that, I might have to clash with him again.
Ah, found you.
You're working hard, Isagi.
Naruhaya.
Have you decided on your next opponent?
No, not yet.
Is that so?
If we lose once more, we're finished. It's really nerve-wracking.
True, but I still don't want to add a weak player to the team.
Yeah. So I've been thinking,
we need to take a risk.
In what sense?
After all, you and I are the ones who won't be chosen if we lose.
We're the same, right?
Scary, isn't it?
My teammate is Barou, and yours is Nagi, man.
In this situation, there's no way we'd be chosen.
Maybe for you, but you're still...
No need for politeness.
After all, the one I want,
is Nagi.
It's not you, Isagi.
You should have realized too.
If you don't add truly strong ones to your team, you can't move forward.
Also, if you want to realize your dream of becoming the world's best striker,
you can't hold back here.
If you run, it's over.
Let's crush each other, Isagi.
Our dreams are at stake.
Don't be a coward.
This is Blue Lock.
This guy...
It suits me. Actually, I was hoping to play against you too.
Then it's decided.
YOICHI ISAGI & SEISHIRO NAGI VS ASAHI NARUHAYA & SHOUEI BAROU
MATCHING APPROVED
Come on, Isagi.
-This is your 50th attempt.
-Okay!
Too obvious.
Barou's weapon is his super accurate mid-range shot.
A shot from the left side of the goal, with a maximum range of 27 meters.
Also, thanks to his extraordinary physique,
he crushes his way into that range.
Right?
Correct.
This is bad, Isagi. I can't practice this against you.
I don't care about playing them, but do you have a plan?
Honestly, I won't know until we face them.
Yeah, you're right.
Unlike a normal match, the teams here are much smaller.
That's why one-on-one encounters become so much more important.
Right.
The only way to figure out how to beat Barou is to play against him.
It's a total gamble.
For us to survive,
we'll need to find the individual strength to beat Barou
during the match.
Alright, I'll start the match marking Barou.
Isagi, you take the small fry.
Got it.
Let's crush each other, Isagi.
Our dreams are at stake.
Crushing these guys will allow me to improve myself and advance to the next stage.
If I lose here,
it means this is the limit of my ability.
That's enough, small fry.
I'm going to sleep.
Don't get in my way during tomorrow's match.
Go play somewhere else, loser.
Understood, king.
Damn it.
I don't want it to end yet.
CARAMEL
TIME REMAINING UNTIL THE MATCH
2ND STAGE
2-ON-2 RIVALRY BATTLE
I've been looking forward to this, king.
Did you practice kneeling?
You're dead.
You're going to be my slave.
Naruhaya.
I'm really going to crush you, so don't hold back.
You didn't have to say that.
He has a crazy stance.
Bring it on, king.
Let's go one-on-one.
If I can't beat him, I won't get anywhere.
You call that dribbling?
Your timing and use of space are trash.
Do you realize who you're facing?
Show some respect.
Damn. Isagi!
Seriously? I have to stop him.
Naruhaya made his move too.
What should I do now? No.
I should stay put. Barou's range is 27 meters.
What? This is 28... No, the distance should be at least 29 meters, right?
So Barou is improving himself in Blue Lock too.
This is not good, Isagi. His range is gradually increasing.
Yeah.
Still, I have to figure something out during the match. I will figure it out.
I'll find a way to win one-on-ones.
Leaving Barou aside, if I can get past this guy one-on-one,
we'll have a fifty-fifty chance.
Damn it, he's so persistent.
Is my dribbling insufficient even against Naruhaya?
So should I send it exactly where Nagi wants?
No, I'm not skilled enough to deliver such a pass.
Naruhaya is blocking the passing lanes
and Barou will intercept any inaccurate pass.
Crap! What should I do?
Pass, Isagi. It doesn't matter how, just pass to me...
Pass to the opening you see!
Where are you passing, loser?
You can't get past me with such a weak pass.
I know, king.
Forget him, I've finally found it.
How to defeat you.
When I move forward and stop, I can't avoid Barou's individual pressure.
So the trick is to make them follow me.
Because that's what happened back then too.
The things I did instinctively are starting to make sense.
They're becoming a reproducible formula.
I don't need special passes.
I can bring the ball to life with my first touch.
Did you see my rhythm?
Take it if you can, king.
I am the god of this field.
Nagi, at what speed are you evolving?
We can win this, Isagi.
The rest is up to you.
Did he find the formula to win in one-on-one just like that?
I can control the ball behind me.
I won't lose anymore.
Bastard.
I'll crush you.
Yes.
Come, Isagi. Let's both pressure him.
What? What about Naruhaya?
No problem.
He's the king. After losing to us, he's in no state to pass.
Barou! I'm open!
Shut up, small fry.
I...
Got it!
Nice, Isagi! Send it!
I won't allow it!
Nagi's weapon is ball control.
Against Nagi, who can turn a ball coming from behind like earlier
into a goal,
the defense will position themselves so he can't turn forward.
Taking advantage of that,
he'll get past the opponent with an unpredictable first touch.
That's Nagi's one-on-one strategy!
But they're already on guard against that.
So next time, against defenses that keep their distance like Naruhaya,
Nagi, utilizing the gap that forms,
will be able to advance and create plays as he wishes.
So a pass sent to Nagi can even be as hard as a shot.
This time, different from before,
it will be a soft,
'black hole' control!
Since Naruhaya kept his distance, he can't block the shot.
This is Nagi's power.
A control that gives life to the ball and
a control that kills the ball.
By using these two controls,
Nagi Seishiro's formula is complete!
Alright, 3 more left.
I also want to find a way to win in one-on-one!
Cut the racket, fools.
Both of you,
I can defeat by myself!
Shit! It's the same as Rin!
That was close!
This guy's sense for goal is insane.
I can't let him shoot again.
The loose ball is mine!
Naruhaya? He came so fast!
Pass, small fry!
Got it, king!
Damn it!
Damn it.
The situation is bad. Barou and Nagi's skills are pretty much at the same level.
In that case, this match rests in Naruhaya's and my hands.
Isagi.
Do you know why I wanted to play against you?
Huh? Isn't it because you want Nagi?
Partly true.
My real goal was
because I thought I could defeat you, Isagi.
Since we've fought together until now, I know.
What you can and can't do.
Isagi, you're not someone who can fight head-to-head.
This bastard,
even though you can't score on your own like Chigiri, Kunigami, and Bachira,
you've made it this far by having those around you carry your ass.
You're not a genius like Nagi or Barou.
You and I,
we're both average people.
What are you doing, Isagi?
Pass the ball!
Damn it!
Pathetic.
Isagi, we're stopping it!
Here it comes.
Barou's attack!
-Did he pass?
-Pass it back, small fry.
No way.
I also want to catch up to the geniuses.
Shit! Naruhaya's weapon,
Mine is sneaking behind.
I can't even beat Naruhaya!
Blue Lock, Extra Time.
Welcome.
Nice to meet you again, Bachira.
BACHIRA MEGURU
That was a good bath.
Why are you walking around stark naked?
What? I'm returning to the form I was born in because I'm human.
What kind of argument is that?
Just when I thought I'd made a new friend, he turns out to be weird!
Stark.
What?
I admire your free style, but at least cover your front.
Otherwise, I'll punish you for glamorous exhibitionism.
My bad.
But it feels insanely good.
Should we do it together?
I'm stripping!
ITOSHI RIN
What do you two think you're doing?
Isn't there a 'normal' person in this room?
-You're one to talk?